#### BHAGHIRATHI KUNDU

# Boston MA-02120 | kundu.b@northeastern.edu | 857-891-4661 | Portfolio | LinkdIn | GitHub

#### **SUMMARY**

A recent graduate with Master's in Information Systems, and years of experience as a Data Analyst. Proficient in Tableau and Power BI dashboard creation, as well as creating pipelines using SQL and Python. Worked in Pharmaceuticals and Telecommunications industry.

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming language:** SQL, Python, HTML, CSS, JAVA **Database:** MySQL, Oracle18c, SQL Server, PostgreSQL **Analytics:** Data visualization, Data integration, Data Quality

**Data Integration:** Talend, Alteryx

Data Visualization: Tableau, Power BI, Qlikview, Advance Microsoft Excel

**Tools:** MySql Workbench, SQL Developer, SSMS, MS-Office, HP Quality Center, Github, Eclipse, Netbeans, Jupyter Notebook **Machine Learning Techniques:** Regression, Classification, Feature Engineering, model selection and evaluation, A/B Testing, EDA

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Vertex Pharmaceuticals, Greater Boston, MA

Jan 2020 - Aug 2020

# Data Analyst Intern

- Assembled complex data sets that meet reporting and analytics requirements from business stakeholders and modified existing queries increasing the efficiency by 20%, saving time, managing data and rebuilt all the related dashboards
- Worked with the Quality Information System Management team to build 10 new dashboards and improve existing dashboards by migrating to BI tools such as Power BI and Tableau from Advanced Microsoft Excel
- Developed ad-hoc reports and data extracts using Microsoft Excel pivot tables to support daily business operations with systems like Veeva, SAS, Oracle Corporations and satisfy regulatory requests, reducing complexity for the team reading from tabular formats
- Analyzed performance data of vendors using SQL, performed data reconciliations and resolving monthly inconsistencies between data sources to ensure proper reporting to regulatory bodies
- Experienced successful implementation of strategic initiatives; collecting, analyzing, and synthesizing large datasets to identify problems and propose solutions, such as reducing the key quality drivers from 5 to the most impactful 3

# Tech Mahindra Ltd, Pune, India

Nov 2015 - May 2018

Data Analyst, AT&T

- Worked for AT&T client with analyzing data to identify deliverables, gaps and inconsistencies in agile environment, reducing the lead time to create deliverables by 10 days
- Interacted with Business to understand the requirements and build ETL pipelines using SQL and Python, combining 4 data warehouses into 1, in preparation for geographical analysis
- Created dynamic Tableau Dashboards identifying the top revenue generating plans of US geographic areas, increasing efficiency of analysis by 30%
- Collaborated with internationally located team of 10 members to create application system's analysis based on business requirements, ensuring the requirements to meet expectations
- Experienced validation techniques as well as reviewing defects, prioritizing defects, impact analysis by generating executive level dashboards, reducing inaccuracies by 50%

#### **EDUCATION**

# Northeastern University, Boston, MA

Sep 2018 - Dec 2020

Master of Science in Information Systems

Relevant Courses: Big Data Architecture and Governance, Data Science Engineering Methods and Tools, Advance Database Management, Designing Data Architecture Business Intelligence, Business Analysis, User Experience Design/Testing

# Visvesvaraya Technological University, JNNCE, Karnataka, India

Sep 2011 - Jun 2015

Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communication Engineering

#### ACADEMIC PROJECTS

#### Northeastern University, Boston, MA

# **Exploratory Data Analysis - Countries of the world GDP (Predictive modeling)**

**Jan 2019 – Apr 2019** 

 Submitted a research paper that conducted Exploratory Data Analysis to understand the factors that affects a country's GDP (per capita) using Python and Anaconda distribution

# Hyperparameter Database (Python, Grid Search, Random Grid Search)

**Jan 2019 – Apr 2019** 

- Created hyperparameter database for Bike Sharing Application and studied models generated using H20 AutoML function
- Created a Leaderboard for multiple runtimes and assessed the efficiency of models generated based on different metrics

### Business Intelligence and Data Warehousing - AdventureWorks2017 (Power BI, Talend)

Sep 2019 – Dec 2019

- Designed a Data Warehouse from four different geographic locations and various data sources
- Developed strategic BI Dashboards in Microsoft Power BI and Tableau based on product store sales and online sales

# Business Analysis – VR Language App (Tableau)

Sep 2019 – Dec 2019

 Identified and prioritized functional and technical requirements for Virtual Reality Teaching App and created datadriven recommendations and reports using Tableau

#### Restaurant Management Database (PL/SQL-Oracle18c)

Sep 2018 – Dec 2018

 Worked on Oracle18c to automate the process of order fulfillment by implementing stored procedures, triggers and cursors thereby increasing the performance of the restaurant order management and reducing manual efforts by 80%